Xiaohui Chen

Email: xiaohui.chen@tufts.edu

Phone: 339-545-6204 Github: Xiaohui9607

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/xiaohui-chen

Вю

I am a 2nd-year Ph.D. student at Tufts University advised by Prof. Li-ping Liu. My research interest lies in general machine learning, with emphasis on generative modeling, variational inference and graph learning. Before this, I was interested in domain adaptation and generalization, computer vision and robotics.

EDUCATION

Tufts University

Sep. 2021 - present

Ph.D Candidate in Computer Science

Tufts University

Sep. 2019 - May 2021

M.S. in Data Science

Professional Experiences

Machine Learning Research Intern Bytedance, Bellevue, USA Jun. 2022 - Sep. 2022

Project: data sub-sampling algorithm for recommender system.

- Developed data sub-sampling algorithm to boost CTR model iteration.
- Utilized structural information in user-item network to estimate sampling score for each instance.
- Reduced uncertainty of the estimated sampling scores via label propagation.
- Achieved significant improvement over the AUC metric of the CTR model compared to other sub-sampling algorithms.

Student Research Assistant Tufts University, Medford, USA May 2020 - Sep. 2021

Topics : graph learning, abnormal detection, advised by Prof. Li-Ping Liu.

- Developed auto-regressive graph generation models by optimizing the variational lower-bound of the generation orders.
- Improved the AUC scores over anomaly detection tasks by ensembling auto-encoders along with adversarial training.

Topics: video generation in robotics, advised by Prof. Jivko Sinapov and Karen Panetta.

- Developed method that predicts next video frame based on inputs from different modality under robot-object interaction scenario.
- Implemented Partial Derivatives of Boolean Functions(PDBF) algorithm for edge detection using C and C++.

Machine Learning Engineer Cobot Technology, Wuhan, China Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2019

Projects: domain adaptation for data reusability, segmentation for anomaly detection.

- Improved classification accuracy by 18% on new domain data by retraining Variational Auto-encoder with unlabeled new domain data and labeled old domain data.
- Developed model based on MobileNet to detect abnormal screws in semi-finished cellphones with 95.3 recall score.

Software Engineer Intern SuperMap Software, Beijing, China Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

Projects : bicycle sharing system.

- Implemented the query and visualization functions of bicycle location and trajectory.
- Trained an RNN to predict trajectory (79% accuracy), and plan for bike parking using the predictions.

Publications * Equal contribution

Preprints

1. Chen, X., Li, Y., Zhang, A., Liu, L. NVDiff: Graph Generation through the Diffusion of Node Vectors.

Conferences

- Chen, X., Wang, Y., Du, Y., Liu, L. On Normalization in Self-supervised Transformers, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2023, under review.
- 2. Chen, X., Sun, J., Wang, T., Guo, R., Liu, L., Zhang, A. Graph-Based Model-Agnostic Data Subsampling for Recommendation Systems, Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (SIGKDD) 2023, under review.
- 3. Chen, X., He, J., Han, X., Liu, L. Efficient and Degree-Guided Graph Generation via Discrete Diffusion Modeling, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2023
- Chen, X.*, Han, X.*, Hu, J., Ruiz, F., and Liu, L. Order Matters: Probabilistic Modeling
 of Node Sequence for Graph Generation, International Conference on Machine Learning
 (ICML) 2021.
- Chen, X.*, Hosseini, R.*, Panetta, K., and Sinapov, J. A Framework for Multisensory Foresight for Embodied Agents, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2021.
- Chen, X.*, Han, X.*, and Liu, L. GAN Ensemble for Anomaly Detection, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2021.

Journals

- 1. Han, X., Chen, X., Ruiz, F., and Liu, L. Fitting Autoregressive Graph Generative Models through Maximum Likelihood Estimation, Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR)
- Chen, X.*, Chen, X.*, Liu, L. Interpretable Node Representation with Attribute Decoding, Transactions on Machine Learning Research (TMLR)

Professional Services

Conference Reviewer

Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023
 International Conference on ArtificialIntelligence and Statistics (AISTATS) 2023

• Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2023

Teaching Experiences

Tufts University

• Introduction to Machine Learning, Graduate Level

Fall 2020

• Statistical Pattern Recognition, Graduate Level

 $Spring\ 2023$

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C++, C, Shell, Matlab, C#, Java, Javascript.

Libraries & Frameworks: Pytorch, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, ROS.

Tools: Git, Latex, HPC, GDB, Vim, Docker, Valgrind, AWS.

Selected Courses

High Dimension Probability; Information Theory; Stochastic Process; Statistical Pattern Recognition; Convex Optimization; Bayesian Deep Learning; Deep Learning; Reinforcement Learning; Natural Language Processing.